# **Dmitry Zorikhin**

Digital Products Delivery Manager with 12+ years of combined experience in Data Science, R&D and Engineering. Initiated, managed and delivered over 40 data and digital transformation products across Oil and Gas (US, Russia), Steel manufacturing (UAE, India, Russia) and Financial industries (US, Malta) with overall economic benefit >\$20mln.

Portfolio: https://dzorikhin.github.io/portfolio/ GitHub: https://github.com/DZorikhin

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmitry-zorikhin/

### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Digital Products Delivery Manager**

Jan 2022 – present

Emirates Steel Arkan, Digital Centre of Excellence - Metals & Mining, Abu Dhabi, UAE

- Managing the team of Data Scientists and Digital Delivery Specialists
- Implemented Value-In-Use model (25 models + optimization) resulted in > \$5mIn/year/plant savings
- Created portfolio with over 20 digital and data science products according with Company strategy goals
- Developed Digital Product Delivery Framework
- Delivered over 10 data and digital products through internal teams and external partners' network
- Driving adoption of data and digital products through business translation

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | Timeseries analysis | SQL | Git | SAS | Azure | Databricks | Docker | Power BI

### **Senior Associate Data Scientist**

May 2021 - Dec 2021

PwC Malta, Digital Transformation - Financial Services, Malta

- Developed and automated financial statements data extraction tool, processed over 10,000 documents
- Initiated 3 data science projects within Assurance and Tax departments

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | Timeseries analysis | SQL | Power BI

Senior Data Scientist July 2020 – March 2021

NLMK Group, Digital Transformation - Metals & Mining, Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Managed 4 digital products at MVP/production stage with \$400,000/year overall economic benefit
- Created portfolio with 15 digital and data science products according with Company strategy goals
- Led the group of 6 Data Science contractor teams
- Initiated 2 innovative projects for production upgrade (laser cutting technology, hydrostatic pressure monitoring)

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | Deep Learning | Timeseries analysis | SQL | GitLab | Hadoop | Spark | Docker

Data Scientist June 2019 – July 2020

Advisor Energy, Digital Transformation - Oil & Gas, Houston, USA

- Developed data-driven forecasting model for shale oil & gas production with 95% accuracy
- Prepared 8 US oil & gas shale basin reports covering over 80 E&P assets using quarterly updated data
- Data-driven Net Asset Value models | Type/Decline curves analytics | Reserves | Completions

Lead Data Analyst March 2019 – June 2019

Tech stack: Python | JavaScript | Classical ML | RNN | Timeseries analysis | AWS | SQL | Power BI | Git | Docker

SKB Kontur, Business Analytics – Software Development, Yekaterinburg, Russia

• Saved \$40,000/month as the result of notification services analysis of lead company's product Kontur.Extern

Tech stack: SQL | GitLab | Python | Classical ML

## Completion and Well Intervention Engineer

Nov 2015 – March 2019

Sakhalin Energy Investment Company Ltd. (Shell and Gazprom JV) – Oil & Gas, Yuzhno-Sakhalinsk, Russia

- Saved \$2mln/well by optimizing well completion timing execution using engineering data model database
- Initiated and got financial approval for joint cloud-based data project for Wells and Subsurface departments
- Reduced CAPEX worth \$50,000/well by optimizing completion string for workover projects

#### Associate Scientist | Engineer

Nov 2009 – Aug 2014

Ural Federal University | Labfer Ltd. - Science (Optoelectronics, Physics), Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Won and led own grant for scientific research with total amount of funds over \$13,000
- Developed ferroelectric substrates bonding technology for engineering project execution worth \$260,000
- Patent owner "Hysteresis-free High-Temperature Precise Bimorph Actuators" as part of project team

### **EDUCATION**

| MSc Offshore Oil and Gas Engineering                                                                                       | 2014 – 2015 |
|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-------------|
| Diploma with Distinction, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UK                                                           |             |
| Postgraduate studies in the Physics of Condensed Matter Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia | 2013 – 2014 |
| MSc in Innovations Diploma with Distinction, Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia            | 2011 – 2013 |
| BSc of Engineering and Technology in Innovations Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia        | 2007 – 2011 |

### SKILLS, ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS AND RELEVANT CERTIFICATES

• Google Cloud Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals